Ben L. Collado

3806 Drew Ln, Arlington, TX 76017 (817) 894-7949 ben.collado@outlook.com linkedin.com/in/bencollado



#### SUMMARY

Self-motivated system engineer experienced in the successful implementation of high-profile IT projects for Fortune 100 companies and IT operational services. Strong problem solving skills not limited to system administrative tasks, cloud solutions, and virtualization. Broad understanding of IT fundamentals, business processes, and technical programming.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# BravoTech, Dallas, TX Operations Support Analyst

2017-Present

- Provided 24/7/365 operations support for a RHEL, multi-node, distributed system.
- Assisted in the migration of customers from the legacy system into the new build.
- Executed operational system updates and changes into various system environment.
- Troubleshot application connection issues between supply and demand customers.
- Tracked system changes and customer incidents using ServiceNow ticketing system.
- Investigated service interruptions using AppDynamics, Veeam ONE, and SiteScope.

## Verizon Enterprise Solutions, Richardson, TX Junior Consultant / Analyst – Professional Services

2014-2016

- Worked in multiple project teams to fulfill the IT needs of Verizon's customer clients.
- Supported various client change requests in Red Hat Enterprise Linux environments.
- Racked, stacked, and decommissioned various physical servers within a data center.
- Installed Verizon Fios in the Washington D.C. area during emergency work stoppage.

# Travelocity, Southlake, TX Business Analyst Intern

2013-2013

- Utilized SAP Business Objects to create business intelligence financial spreadsheets.
- Coded Jaspersoft iReports functionality into a revenue tracking application for airlines.
- Performed QA tasks for financial quality and integration for Travelocity online bookings.
- Served as system administrator for hundreds of users by creating new IDs, setting permissions, and reactivating accounts for various back end financial system tools.

#### PROFESSIONAL CONSULTING PROJECTS

#### **JetBlue Customer Technology Refresh Project**

Major airliner based in New York that upgraded their IT infrastructure into the Verizon cloud.

- Migrated JetBlue servers from an onsite legacy system into Verizon e-cloud.
- Created RHEL and Centos VMs by using templates located in the cloud's web GUI.
- Configured newly created VMs to reflect client's environment by setting server name, hardware options, gateway, hostname, internal DNS, IP address, and storage volume.
- Documented and published new system build specifications onto internal wiki site.
- Used Appdynamics to identify errors and generate environmental specific reports.

American Airlines and US Airways Passenger Service System (PSS) Migration Project Migrated US Airways kiosk into American Airlines' domain hosted and monitored by Verizon.

Ben Collado Page Two

- Lead the process with both AA and USAir field-techs during onsite failover piloting.
- Troubleshot various kiosk problems by either changing configurations, adding permissions, or by running Windows PowerShell scripts remotely.
- Verified and documented kiosks status and monitoring tools after VHD installation.

#### **Lowes.com Disaster Recovery Project**

Lowes.com, a home improvement retailer that needed to build a disaster recovery environment.

- Created, tested, and deployed UNIX shell scripts by migrating code deployment and performance test scripts and their dependencies from Production into DR
- Installed distributed shell (DSH) into DR environment and developed configuration files.

### **American Airlines eSOA Project**

Primary Verizon contact for eSOA updates for code deployments and promotion of services.

- Worked closely with client via conference calls and email during deployments.
- Placed domains into maintenance mode and opened and closed queue via shell scripts.
- Reconfigured client's DataPower policies and configurations to company specifications.

### **Lowes.com Performance Stress Test**

After a new code release, Lowes.com would administer a load test by generating 80,000 virtual users to perform normal shopping tasks on their RHEL environment for a set amount of time.

- Worked with customer engineers to administer test with client via teleconferences.
- Performed administrative task of monitoring server CPU levels in real time during test.
- Collected and procured system health logs through various UNIX shell scripts.
- Created reports of test results, pushed data to client's NAS device, and restarted JVMs.

#### **CLASS WORK AND ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

- Executed machine learning algorithms to classify stubleupon.com page contents.
- Utilized AWS EMR and the Hadoop environment to analyze and process Big Data.
- Programmed business applications in Java and developed PC video games in Python.
- Designed project SDLC by practicing agile methodology and using UML notation.

#### **EDUCATION / TRAINING / SKILLS**

### **Master of Science, Information Systems**

University of Texas at Arlington Arlington, TX; 2014; GPA 3.6

### **Bachelor of Science, Information Systems**

University of Texas at Arlington Arlington, TX; 2012

## **Training**

Red Hat System Administration I, Red Hat System Administration II, Architecting on AWS

# **Applications / Tools**

Verizon Terremark Cloud, VMware, AWS, SAP Enterprise Resource Planning, SAP Business Objects, Jaspersoft iReports, Pycharm, NetBeans, Eclipse, SQL Query Builder, Remedy, ServiceNow, AppDynamics, ExtraHop, SiteScope

#### **Programming Languages**

UNIX, Python, Java, C#, XML, HTML, SQL

#### **OTHERS**

- Association of Information Technology Professionals of UTA; Vice President 2012
- Fluent in conversational and written English and Tagalog (Filipino)